Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar:Hi.Good morning.
各位早上好
Good morning.Welcome back.
早上好 很高兴又见到大家
Hope you had a wonderful break.
希望你们都度过了一个愉快的假期
That you took time to recover,to de-stress.
恢复元气 释放压力
And as it happens,this is the topic today.
这也是今天的主题
We'll continue from where we left off before break.
我们接着上节课继续讲
So remember we talked about the idea that in fact,
上回我们提出 事实上
stress wasn't the problem,
压力不是问题
which was the most interesting,surprising- but in retrospect,
这是压力研究最有趣 最令人惊讶
obvious finding of the research on stress.
现在看来 也是最显著的发现
That stress in and of itself is actually good,
压力本身其实是件好事
just like in athletics,just like in sports,
就像在体育运动中
when we stress a muscle,the muscle develop- it grows.
我们给肌肉以压力 肌肉就会发展 增长
When we stress ourselves psychologically,emotionally,we grow.
我们心理上情感上给予自己压力 我们就会成长
We become more resilient.We become stronger.
变得更开朗 更坚强
It's not good for a person
从小在无菌环境里长大
who's just born to be put in a sterile environment
从未受过外界任何压力
and be protected from all the stresses of the outside world,
对人是不利的
such as bacteria for example,which stresses the system.
比如影响机体的细菌
Cause it forces to grade antibodies.
会使人体产生抗体
It's not good for us to be in a sterile environment,
所以长在无菌环境中对我们是不利的
not physically- whether it's in a closing environment as babies,
不仅指生理上婴儿的密闭环境
not physically in terms of not doing sports,
缺乏运动
not pushing ourselves,and also not mentally and emotionally-
还包括心理及情感
which is why I said you know time and again: I wish you fail more
所以我常常说 我希望你们遭受更多的失败
Because I think it is important to go through hardships,
因为艰难困苦
through difficulties.
能给予我们极大的锻炼
And in fact,we are going to talk about failure
结束"目标设定"的课程后
right after we finish up with the "Goal setting" lecture,
就会开始关于失败的课程
when we discuss perfectionism,
我们会讨论完美主义
which is all about our approach toward failure.
也就是对待失败的态度
So stress is not the problem.The problem is lack of recovery.
所以问题不是压力 而是缺乏休整
And that is what we don't have enough of in our culture-
不仅仅在哈佛 我们的文化中
not just at Harvard.
都对休息缺乏重视
Most workplaces- there is not enough place for recovery;
大多数办公场所 都没有足够的地方进行休整
in most school,most universities- which explains
大多数学校 大学
why levels of stress translate themselves to chronic stress,
所以压力转变为慢性压力
translate themselves to chronic anxiety,
变成了长期焦虑
translate themselves to depression.
变成了抑郁症
It's because we don't have the recovery.
就因为我们没有休整
And we talked about recovery on the a few levels-
我们还讲了不同层面的休整
so just a quick recap.
快速回顾一下
We talked about recovery on the micro level,which is,
微观层面上 休整可以是
for example,every 90 minutes of sprint,15 minutes break-
比如 每冲刺90分钟 就休息15分钟
instead of marathon runners,being sprinters.
不要做马拉松运动员 要做短跑运动员
It's 15 minutes meditation.
可以是15分钟冥想
It's a one hour lunch,
一小时的午餐
where we really give ourselves time to recover.
给自己时间好好休整
It's going to the gym on a regular basis.
可以是定期去健身房
It's the 15 minutes of listening to our favorite piece of music,
听15分钟喜欢的音乐
speaking to a friend or whatever it is.
与朋友聊天 等等
The recovery on the micro level.
这是微观层面上的休整
And people who recover,who have recovered during their work day-
上班时间进行休整的人...
and this is research done across the river
河对岸的Teresa Amabile和Leslie Perlow等人
by people like Teresa Amabile or Leslie Perlow,
经过研究发现
show how important it is in a workplace to have recoveries
如果工作场所能提供休整
and people who do it are more productive,
能使员工效率更高 更有创意
more creative and in the long term,also happier.
并且长期来看 会更幸福
Higher levels of job satisfaction.
提高工作满意度
Recovery also on the mezzo level the full night sleep,
中度休整包括一夜好眠
the day off during once a week at least.
每周至少休息一天
Time off recreate so that we can create.
放松休息以便重新投入工作
And finally,the vacations.Holidays.Longer periods.
最后还有假期 节假日 长假
You see,the other thing that happens
如果我们片刻不停的运作
when we are constantly on the run is that
会发生什么
we miss the beauty that's all around us and within us.
我们错过了身边和自身的风景
We miss the real potential for happiness,for joy,
错过了获得快乐幸福
for appreciation that surrounds us day in and day out.
欣赏日常生活中美的机会
And that's why we take things for granted.
所以我们把一切都当做理所当然
Because we don't take the time to appreciate,to savor.
因为我们没有花时间去欣赏体会
And it's not natural to do so.
这有悖自然
I mean can you imagine?
你们能想象
Can you imagine a lion living in our modern world?
一头狮子生活在现代世界?
Can you imagine a lion working at McKinsey?
在麦肯锡或者投资银行上班
Or in investment banking? Or being on the tenure track?
或者成为终身教授?
It's unnatural.You know what a lion needs to do is yawn.
这很反常 大家都知道狮子要打瞌睡
They need to play.It is natural.
要追逐嬉戏 这才正常
And remember what we talked about
还记得我们头几节课
during the first couple of lectures?
怎么说的吗
The constraint view of human nature-
人性中视野的局限性
nature to be commanded must be obeyed.
服从权力
Our nature dictates that we need recovery.
人的天性需要休整
All animals do.
所有动物都是
And when we frustrate a psychological,physical need,
如果我们违背心理或生理需求
we pay a price for it,whether it's the need for recovery
就会为此付出代价 无论是需要休整
or the need for physical exercise,
需要身体锻炼
or the need for certain vitamins or protein.
还是需要某种维生素或蛋白质
We pay a price for it.And the key is,
我们会为此付出代价 关键是
to introduce these natural recovery periods into our lives.
将这种本能的休整期引入我们的生活
And here is the key.The key is focus.
关键就是集中注意
Focus on both work as well as recovery.
同时关注工作与休整
So remember the question that we asked before break.
想一下我们节前提出的问题
What makes some individuals succeed despite
处于相同的现代社会 拥有相似的雄心壮志
living in a modern world or living with ambition and success?
为什么有些人能获得成功?
Well these individuals know how to focus
他们知道
when they work,when they play.
何时聚焦工作 何时聚焦玩乐
To use a cliché,they work hard and they play hard.
套句老话 他们努力工作玩得开心
What does that mean specifically? First of all,in recovery.
具体是什么意思呢?首先 要休整
They understand that quantity affects quality.
他们明白多则劣 少则精
Let me share with you a study that you read about in the book.
我们来看一下诺贝尔奖得主
This is by Nobel Prize winner,
以色列心理学家Daniel Kahneman
the Israeli psychologist Daniel Kahneman.
进行的一项研究
Won Nobel prize for economics,turned positive psychologist.
他曾获得诺贝尔经济学奖 后来成为了积极心理学家
What he wanted to understand was the affective,
他希望研究一天内
the emotional experiences of women during the day.
妇女的情感感情经历
And what he did was ask women to evaluate their experiences
他让一些妇女在经历了某些特定事件后
right after they had that particular experience:
对此经历做出评估:
so what was it like for you?
刚才的感觉怎么样
And they evaluated their experience at work.
这些经历包括工作
They evaluated their experience shopping.
购物
They evaluated their experience
与亲密伴侣 孩子
spending time with their intimate partners,with their children,
共处的时光
having lunch with friends,whatever it was.
与朋友共进午餐 等等
They evaluated how they were doing during the day.
评估一天内她们的心情
The most surprising finding of this result was that
结果令人惊讶
these women did not particularly enjoy time
这些妇女并不特别享受
they spent with their kids.
与孩子共处的时光
Now this result was very surprising to Kahneman.
这一结果让Kahneman很吃惊
When he probed further- he and his co-authors:
他和合作者进一步研究发现
it wasn't the fact that the women didn't love their kids.
这些妇女并不是不爱她们的孩子
I mean they love their kids.
她们很爱孩子
For most of these women,kids were the most meaningful,
对其中大多数人来说 孩子是她们生活中
important thing in their lives.
最有意义 最重要的一部分
However,their experience with their kids
但是 她们与孩子共处的经历
often was not pleasurable- the second component of happiness.
通常并不愉悦 这是快乐的第二个组成成分
very meaningful,but not always pleasurable.
有意义但不愉悦
Why? When they probed further,they found out exactly why.
为什么呢?他们进一步研究揭露了确切的原因
Because these women,when they were with their kids,
因为这些妇女与孩子共处时
they were not really with their kids,
并不是真正全身心与孩子在一起
meaning they were on the phone at the same time,
可能同时还打电话
or doing email,or thinking about what they had,
或者写邮件
they did earlier at work,or what they had to do later at home.
思考上班的事 或者要做的家务
They were distracted.And they were not present with their kids.
她们一心多用 并没有全身心与孩子一起
Now individually,discreetly,
单独来看
they may have very enjoyed being on the phone with a friend,
她们可能和乐意与朋友讲电话
or doing work,or thinking about work,
工作 思考工作
or thinking about what they have to do later.
或者等下要做的事
Each discreet individual activity may have been a lot of fun.
这些活动单独发生可能很有趣
But together,it was too much of a good thing.
但是同时进行 就乐极生悲了
And quantity affects quality.
量影响质
I mean,thinking about the following analogy.
听听这个类比
Think about the following analogy.
Think about your favorite piece of music
想想你闭着眼睛 全神贯注地
and listening to it with your eyes close and focus.
听你最喜欢的音乐
So your favorite piece of music- if it's like mine,
我最喜欢的歌是
probably is Whitney Houston's "And I will Always Love You".
惠特尼休斯顿的《我会永远爱你》
Thank you.Yes.
谢谢
There's another one here with good taste in music.
英雄所见略同
And you listen to Whitney Houston
于是你听着惠特尼休斯顿的歌
or whatever your favorite piece of music is.
或者其他你最喜欢的音乐
You eyes close and you focus.
闭着眼睛 全神贯注
Then you rate it on a scale of one to ten.
然后从一到十打个分数
And of course,perfect ten: you are touched.
绝对是满分十分
You are moved.You are inspired.
你深受感动 灵感迸发
And then you listen to your second most favorite piece of music,
于是又开始听第二喜欢的音乐
which,if it is like mine,
如果是我
it's the chorus piece from Beethoven's Ninth.
会选贝多芬的《第九交响曲》
And you listen to it.You focus on it.
你全神贯注地听着
And again,you rate it on a scale of one to ten.
然后从一到十打分
Not quite high as "And I will Always Love You",
没有《我会永远爱你》这么高
but it's a nine and a half.
但也有9.5分了
And then,and then,for maximum effect,
接着 为了达到最大效果
you take the two pieces together and play them.
你把两首歌同时播放
And what do you get? A nineteen and a half,right?
结果怎样? 19.5分吗
No.Not a ten.Not even a five.It's noise.
不 不是10分 连5分也没有 纯粹是噪音
This is modern life for you.This is modern life.
这就是现代生活
We have activities; we have so many wonderful things in our lives
我们进行各种活动 生活中有这么多美好的东西
But we have too many of them.
但是又多过头了
And you know what that often does?
这会怎样呢?
It very often leads to guilt and frustration.
这常常会导致内疚 沮丧
Why? Because I say to myself: how is that possible?
为什么 因为我对自己说 这怎么可能
I love doing what I'm doing!
我喜欢做这些事
I'm so fortunate to have so many amazing,wonderful things,
生活中能有这么多美好人事物
people,experiences in my life.
我真是太幸运了
And yet I fail to be happy!
但我竟然不快乐
There must be something wrong with me.
我肯定有什么不对劲
No,there's nothing wrong with you.
不 你没有什么不对劲
It's perfectly natural,just like you will not be able to enjoy
这正常得很 就好像你不可能
the two pieces of music played together even though
同时欣赏两首歌
individually they are your two most favorite pieces of music.
即使它们分别都是你最喜欢的音乐
Too much of a good thing.Quantity does affect quality.
过犹不及 多则劣 少则精
You know,this happens constantly.
这种情况常发生
It happened to me two years ago
两年前 我教授积极心理学时
when I was teaching positive psych.
就发生过
It was one month into this semester,
刚开学一个月
and it just didn't make sense to me: why wasn't I happy?
我很困惑 为什么我不快乐
The class was doing well.
教学工作很顺利
I was enjoying the class.I was doing a lot of work- consulting.
我很喜欢上课 同时还担任咨询顾问工作
I was speaking around the country
在全国进行关于积极心理学
about positive psychology,about Israel.
及以色列的讲座
I was writing and doing all the things that I love,
写作出书
that I care about,that I'm passionate about.
做各种我喜欢在乎 充满热情的事
Spending time with my family.
和家人在一起
And I took a step back and I realized "too much of a good thing".
于是我退一步 发现我"过犹不及"了
And as soon as I cut the activities,
一旦我减少活动量
happiness levels went back up again.
幸福指数又重新提升
Quantity affects quality.
多则劣 少而精
Researchers on relationships and love,
两性关系研究者
the Hendricks couple (Susan & Clyde Hendrick),say,
Hendrick夫妇认为
"Love and sex are affected negatively by stress.
"爱与性与压力成反比
If we can help people to simplify their lives,
如果我们能帮助人们简化生活
thus reducing their stress levels,it is very likely that
降低压力水平
people's relationships would be enriched greatly.
那他们关系的将会大大改善
Moreover,the positive aspects of their lives
更重要的是 他们生活中的积极方面
would be enriched accordingly."
也会相应得到提升"
It affects every area of our lives,whether it's our love life,
它会影响我们生活的方方面面
whether it's our experience with our kids,
无论是爱情生活 与孩子共处
whether it's our experience doing work or reading,
工作 阅读
spending time with friends or writing.
与朋友共处 写作
There can be too much of a good thing.
都可能造成过犹不及
So if we have lunch and we use lunch as recovery,
所以如果我们把午餐作为休整
and at the same time we are on the phone and doing email,
同事还打电话 写邮件
that's not recovery; that's simply more stress.
那就不是休整了 而是更多的压力
But if we have just lunch and focus on our eating and enjoy it,
但如果我们只是享用午餐 享受美食
or just spend time with people we love,that's recovery.
或者只是与爱的人呆在一起 那就是休整
The key is focus.The same thing applies to work.
专注是关键 工作也是如此
Now it's not possible in our world today,
但是在当今社会
certainly not in leadership positions
尤其是处于领导地位
which many of you already got or will assume in the future,
你们很多人可能已经...或者将来即将体验
it's not possible to eliminate multi-tasking.
不可能避免多任务
The key though is to reduce it.
关键就是减少任务
Just a quick show of hands: how many people here,
我们来统计一下 在座有多少人
while you are doing work that requires concentration,
从事需要集中注意力的工作时
that requires focus- whether it's writing,or doing reading,
无论是写作 阅读
or anything else that requires concentration-
或者其他什么需要专注的工作时
how many people here have their emails on at the same time?
有多少人同时还开着邮箱的?
OK.It's the majority.
很好 占大多数
It's most people in the West that,who do that.
几乎所有人都这样
I used to do that too.Until I found out about this research.
我以前也这样 后来我读到了这项研究
When you have your email on,
当你开着邮箱
while you are doing work that requires concentration,
从事需要集中注意的工作时
it is equivalent to taking off 10 IQ points.10 IQ points.
等于智商减少10 整整10分
Now I don't know about you; but I can't spare 10 IQ points.
我不知道各位怎样 但我可不能少10点智商
Now for comparison's sake,if you lose a whole night sleep,
作为比较 如果你一整晚通宵
so if you haven't slept for 36 hours,
36小时不睡
your IQ is reduced by the equivalent of 10 points.
也等于智商减少10点
Another point of comparison: if you smoke marijuana,
另一项比较: 如果你抽大麻
if you smoke grass,your IQ's reduced by 4 points.
智商会减少4
So if you have- look I mean it's the choice-
所以如果你...面临选择
more fun,less IQ points.Well but don't inhale.
是要找乐子 还是降低智商 但千万别吸毒
Now I hope you didn't record that there.Here is the study.
希望你们没录到前面
This was done in the University of London.
伦敦大学进行过一项研究
The IQ of those who try to juggle messages
上班时发短信的人
at work fell by 10 points,
智商会降低10
the equivalent of missing a whole night sleep,
与整晚通宵的人一样
and more than doubled 4.4 seen after smoking marijuana.
抽大麻才4.4点 比这2倍还多
Look,nothing will happen
听着 如果你关邮箱2小时
if you switch off your email for 2 hours at a time.
不会发生什么大不了的事
Nothing will happen.Except for thing that will happen.
什么也不会发生 除了这种情况:
You'll get another message saying,
你可能会收到另一条消息问:
you know- the server may have been down or,
服务器是不是当了?
so you are not sure you got my email.
你没收到我的邮件?
Right you get those emails,
其实你收到邮件了
if you don't respond for about an hour or two,
如果一两小时内不回复
the server may have been down.
对方就以为服务器挂了
But other than that,nothing will happen,
除此以外 什么也不会发生
if you don't respond to emails,
即使你不回复
if you don't have your emails on for two,three hours.
即使把邮箱关个两三小时
Nothing will happen if you don't answer the phone every moment.
同样 就算你不是每个电话都接 也不会怎么样
Unless you are an ambulance driver,
除非你是救护车司机
in which case you should have it on.
那还是开着电话吧
But otherwise,it's fine.Switch it off.
除此以外 都可以关了电话
Doing less- and when you do less,you get so much more done.
少做点事 可以完成得更多
Creativity goes up.Productivity goes up.Work satisfaction goes up
创造力提升 效率提高 工作满意度提升
Because when we are distracted,
因为我们分心时
there can't be too much of a good thing.
就会过犹不及
I've spoken about so many techniques already.
我提到过很多技巧
I speak about some more about journaling,
比如记日记
about doing gratitude exercise,about writing a gratitude letter.
表达感激 写感谢信
We are going to talk about doing more physical exercise.
今天我们还会讲到生理锻炼
We talk about act of kindness and so many things,but
仁爱之举 等等
really the key thing is actually not to do the additional things,
但是最关键不是要多做事
but to do less,or rather to identify the things that
而是少做 或者说是明确
you really,really want to do with your life and do them.
你真心想做的 然后坚定不移地执行
Because quantity affects quality.
因为多则劣 少则精
Tim Kasser,a humanistic psychologist
人本主义心理学家Tim Kasser
has done research on time affluence.
做过一项关于时间充裕的研究
As we know from research,
我们已经知道
material affluence matters very little to our well being,
物质充裕对于我们的幸福感影响不大
beyond having our basic needs met,
基本需求得到满足之外
hardly even affects our well being.
几乎不会影响我们的幸福感
However,what does affect our well being
但是 的确会影响我们幸福感的
is what Kasser calls "time affluence",
是Kasser所说的"时间充裕"
which is the feeling that we have time,
这是一种感觉 我们感到时间充裕
the feeling that we can savor the things that we are doing,
感到我们能充分享受手头所做的事
that we are not constantly chasing our own shadow,
而不是竹篮打水 做无用功
that we are not constantly running around and feeling stressed.
东奔西跑 压力巨大
And people who have time affluence in their lives-
时间充裕的人
that is a good predictor of well being.
往往容易获得幸福感
And that is something that we can introduce.
这点我们可以详细介绍
Granted,more difficult in a place like this
即使现代生活
where there are so many appealing distractions.
充斥着种种使人分心的诱惑
I'm using the word "distraction" here,
我用了"使人分心"这个词
even though many of these things
虽然这些诱惑
may be wonderful,amazing,meaningful things to you.
对你来说可能美好精彩 意义非凡
But when they all come together,
但如果同时出现
it becomes unfortunately the experience of distraction.
很不幸 会让你分心
You know modern world functionality is being pitted against fun.
现代社会的运转常常与快乐对立
The questions is
所以问题是
how do you make our life fun as well as functionality,
如何让我们的生活 充满乐趣同时又正常运转
which is parellel to the present and future benefit.
类似于当下与未来的利益
And what we know is that we recovery,fun recovery in our lives-
我们知道要休整 重拾生活中的乐趣
listening to our favorite piece of music and
听喜欢的音乐
only listening to our favorite piece of music and one at a time;
而且每次只能一首
or having lunch with friends
或者与朋友共进午餐
or nice dinners in our house with our roommates.
与室友在家一起享用晚餐
When we savor the time together,
当我们一起享受时光时
it's not just fun,it's also functional.
不仅仅是快乐 而且有用
It's also a formal recovery.
是正式休整
The question is how do you reconcile? How do you do the 'and'?
问题是如何调和快乐与有用?
Cause remember the question that positive psychologists ask:
还记得积极心理学提出的问题吗
what do people who are happy,healthy AND successful do?
快乐 健康且成功的人士 是如何达成这一切的?
And once they started to ask this question,
这一问题一经抛出
it opened up all the possibilities,
就打开了所有可能性
all the answers came rushing in literally.
出现了各种各样的回答
And one of the answers is- focus on work,focus on recovery.
其中一种回答是 聚焦工作 聚焦休整
You'll get much more done and much better.
则工作效率更高 质量更佳
One of the shortest- or the shortest word-
英语语言中最短的
in the English language and yet people are so afraid of it,
但又人人害怕的单词是
saying "no"-
"不"
whether it's saying no to people who ask you something,
无论是对寻求帮助的人说不
again saying no empathically,or saying no to opportunities.
还是对眼前的机遇说不
Because essentially when we are saying no to some opportunities,
因为我们对某些机遇说"不"
when we are saying no to some offers,
对某些提议说"不"时
we are saying yes to ourselves.
其实是对自己说"是"
And how do we choose what do we say no to
那如何选择对什么说"不"
and what do we say yes to? C
对什么说"是"呢
By simply asking what do I really,really,really want to do.
很简单 问自己究竟想要什么
Simplifying- doing less,rather than more.
简化 宁缺毋滥
The key though is to reach optimum levels of simplicity.
关键就是找到最适宜的简化程度
Because we don't want to simplify too much
因为过于简化
and go to the other extreme.
就会走向另一个极端
You see,in a way,it works,as many things work,
和其他事物及诸多心理学显现一样
many psychological phenomenon work,in a curve linear manner.
简化与效率是以曲线形式存在
Let me explain.
我来解释一下
So let's say we have a graph where this is amount of work.
这张图表的X轴代表工作量
And on this axis we have productivity,creativity and happiness.
Y轴代表效率 创造力与快乐
The way it work,the way it looks,is this way,meaning:
两者的关系是这样的
if our amount of work is too high,
如果工作量太大
that's when we experience the TBD,Too Busy Disorder.
就会发生TBD 即忙碌紊乱症
We are unhappy; we are not creative; and we are not productive.
我们会不快乐 缺乏创造力 效率低下
This is the burn-out.
精疲力竭
We may be productive and creative for a short while,
也许短时间能效率和创造力能维持一段时间
but this is the burn-out phase.
但这点代表精疲力竭
On the other hand,if we do too little,that's also not good.
另一方面 如果我们什么也不做 那也不好
And very similar consequences- we are unhappy;
后果相似 我们会不快乐
we are certainly not productive; and we are not creative.
没有效率 缺乏创新
This is extreme procrastination,
这点代表极端拖延
which we will talk about in a minute.
我们马上会讲到
This is over work.
这点代表过度工作
What we want to find is our optimum-
我们要发掘
for each person,this is in a different place.
各自的最适宜点 每个人都不一样
I mean,this graph can be situated here for one person,
有些人 图的位置可能靠这里
and here for another.
有些人可能更靠前
But each person has this optimal level.
但是每个人都会有个最适宜点
And this is where highest level
这点代表了效率 创造力
of productivity,creativity and happiness is.
以及快乐的理想状态
So on the one extreme we have the law of gas
例如气体再少也能充满整个空间
essentially applied to time management.
也适用于时间管理方面
But even if we have very little work,
即使我们工作再少
it will take up all of our time.
它会占用我们所有时间
And then we are not productive,not creative,not happy.
这样我们变得效率低下 缺乏创造力 不快乐
On the other hand,we have- the quote that I've used time
另一方面是...我常常引用JP Morgan的一句话
and again by J.P.Morgan,that he can do a year's work in 9 months
他可以在9个月能完成一年的工作
but not in 12 and the need for time-off.
但不能花12个月 需要休息时间
Where is your optimal level? Where are you? Between these two.
你的理想值在哪里 这两者间你在哪
You need to find out.It's trial and error.
你得自己摸索 反复试验
And it's a lot of error.And that's OK.That's how we learn.
期间会犯很多错误 没关系 我们就是这样学习的
Essentially what we are about is sustainable growth.
本质上 我们关注的就是可持续增长
Henry David Thoreau: "Simplicity,simplicity,simplicity!
梭罗说过"要简单 简单 再简单
I say let your affairs be as two or three,
依我说 你要做的事应当是两三件
and not a hundred or a thousand;
而不是成百上千件
instead of a million count half a dozen...
数上半打 而不要数上百万
In the midst of this chopping sea of civilized life,
在这多变的文明生活的海洋里
such are the clouds and storms and quick sands
云雾 风暴 流沙
and the thousand-and-one items to be allowed for,
和许许多多事情都得考虑
and he must be a great calculator indeed who succeeds.
他要成功 就必须是台出色的计算器
Simplify.Simplify ." This was written around 1840.
简化 再简化" 这段话写于1840年代
How much more do we need to simplify today,in the 21st century?
那到了21世纪 我们还要如何简化呢
And what we are about,again,is sustainable growth.
我们关注的是可持续增长
I've used this metaphor from environmentalism.
这一比喻借鉴自环境保护论
What's sustainable growth? So when a country like Senegal
什么是可持续增长? 比如塞内加尔
is now talking about sustainable growth,what does it mean?
想要进行可持续增长 该如何进行?
It doesn't mean that it wants to freeze progress.
这不是说他们停止增长
It means that it wants to grow,however,in a sustainable way,
而是指他们想要增长 但以一种可持续的方式
which means- "let's take out of the environment
也就说"对环境的损耗
what can be replenished naturally through our help."
要控制在可以人工帮助下自然恢复的范围内"
The exact same thing we are talking about
与我们所说的心理学概念
on the psychological level.
完全一致
We are not talking about a stress-free life,
我们提倡的不是
a life when we don't take out of ourselves,
无需奋斗 无需努力的
when we don't push ourselves,when we don't exert ourselves.
无压生活
What we are talking about
我们提倡的
when we are talking about sustainable growth is that
可持续增长是指
we take out of ourselves,we exert,we stress ourselves
我们努力奋斗 竭尽全力 给予自己一定压力
and we replenish through recovery just enough
然后通过充分的休整得以恢复
so that it is sustainable.
这才是可持续
Because if we don't replenish,then it's not sustainable
因为如果不恢复 那就无法持续
and then we begin to experience anxiety,depression,burn-out,
会出现焦虑 抑郁 疲惫
and so on.
等等情绪
So ask yourself.Where do I in my life need to simplify?
所以问问自己 我的生活需要简化什么
Where do I in my life need to do more?
我的生活还需要做些什么
How can I,in other words,overcome procrastination?
也就是说 该如何克服拖延心理
Going back to our friend.
回到我们朋友那
Because this may be a little bit too extreme.
因为可能有点太极端了
You know 70 percent,more than 70 percent of college students,
全国有70% 超过70%的大学生
nationwide complain about procrastination.
抱怨拖延心理
Not others' procrastination- their own procrastination.
不是别人拖延 而是他们自己拖延
The other 30 percent are in denial.No.
另外30%矢口否认
Over 70 percent.
超过70%
Now procrastination is associated with lower levels of happiness,
拖延与不快乐
weakened physical immune system,
生理免疫系统脆弱
higher levels of stress and could also lead to depression.
压力过大等等都有关联 可能会导致抑郁
Not a very high correlation,
虽然关联程度不高
but there is a positive correlation between the two.
但是两者呈正相关
Fortunately though,there is a lot of research on procrastination
幸运的是 有许多关于拖延的研究
A research that can actually help.
其中一项研究很有帮助
And the research is done at the University of Carleton in Canada,
这项研究是由加拿大卡尔顿大学
where they have an actual procrastination research group.
拖延心理研究小组进行的
And I went,I browsed them...
我浏览了...
You can go on their website- great website,
你可以访问他们的网站 做得很不错
and there are great pictures there.
还有许多有价值的照片
And one of the set of the pictures
其中一组照片
is from their yearly conference on procrastination,
是来自他们年度的讨论拖延心理的会议
which is remarkable.
该会议意义重大
So here are some photos from that very important conference.
这些是会议的照片
So on the first day they all arrived
所有人于第一天抵达
and they got together for a meal.
进行了聚餐
And after they got together for meal,they had another a meal
聚餐后 他们又吃了一顿
because they were hungry a few hours later.
因为几小时后有人又饿了
And then the following day they just hang out and walked around.
第二天 他们结伴出游 四处走走
It was a beautiful place after all.
校园风景很美
And afterwards,they had some food together.
然后 一起吃了点东西
And then,you know,food begets food so they ate some more.
然后 一顿接一顿 他们又吃了几顿
And at the end of the conference,
到了会议最后一天
they really felt like they got,they accomplished a lot.
他们觉得完成不少任务
You know they practiced what they preached.
实践了他们倡导的内容
So they had a photo of all of them together right here.
于是拍了一张全家福作为结尾
Actually they do fascinating work
事实上 他们对拖延
and very important work on procrastination.
进行了精彩的重要的研究
So here are some of the results,
以下是部分结果
some of the important results for overcoming procrastination.
如何克服拖延
First,most important one,simple,easy to implement and it works
首先 最重要的一点 很简单 容易实践且有效
It's what they call "the 5 minute take-off".
他们称之为"5分钟起步"
One of the things they found with,just about all procrastinator
他们发现所有拖延者都有一个共同点:
is that they have a misunderstanding of what it takes to act.
他们对行动的要求有所误解
Procrastinators,the world over,think that in order to act,
全世界的拖延者都以为 要有所行动
they first need to be inspired.
必须先受到激励
I have to feel the vibes,before I start the EC 10 problem set.
我必须感受到共鸣 才能开始编写经济学10号课程的题库
I really have to be inspired
我必须有所灵感
before I write this paper for Lit and Arts.
才能下笔写文学艺术论文
But you know what? That's not how it works.
但事实并不是这样
That's not how it works.
并不是这样
It's not about first changing our attitude,i.e.
第一步并不是改变态度
becoming inspired and then acting.
即受到激励 然后行动
It usually works the other way around.
恰恰相反
We first need to start acting,behavior,
要先开始行动
that will then affect our attitude.
行动会慢慢地影响我们的态度
Because very often once we start,we are on a roll.
因为通常行动开始后 我们会有惯性
Or sometimes,a few times,
或者有时候
during let's say the 90 minutes sprint,
在90分钟冲刺中
we have to restart the 5 minute.
我们需要重新5分钟起步
I don't know if you,if you've noticed this,but if you haven't,
我不知道你们是否留意到了
it's something that I really like to share with you.
如果还没有 我想跟大家分享一下
By now,you know we know one another pretty well.
现在我们应该互相非常了解了
Or you know me pretty well.
或者你们非常了解我
So if you don't know this,I think you should know this.
如果你们不知道 我想你们应该知道
I am extremely,extremely passionate about positive psychology.
我非常非常热衷积极心理学
I love positive psychology.
我喜欢积极心理学
But you know,sometimes when I get up in the morning,
但有时候 我早上起床
and I write something about positive psychology
写关于积极心理学的文章
or prepare a lecture on positive psychology
准备积极心理学讲座
or read positive psychology,sometimes I don't feel like starting
或者阅读积极心理学文章 有时候我完全不在状态
You know,this is actually a very big surprise for my wife.
这让我太太大吃一惊
And it only came up just a couple of years into our marriage,
那时我们刚结婚几年
while I told her,
我告诉她
"yeah,sometimes I really don't feel like getting up."
"是的 有时候我都没心情起床"
She said,"how's that possible?
她说"这怎么可能
I mean,you know you get up in the morning
你早上起床
and then you go to your computer,and you start to work on it."
打开电脑 开始工作"
Yes,exactly! Because I know the 5 minute take-off.
是的 没错 因为我了解5分钟起步
And sometimes within a 90 minute session,
有时候在90分钟时间段里
I have to do another 5 minute take-off
我不得不再做一次5分钟起步
because my energy levels are drained.
因为我感到精力不支
So either take time off to recover,
所以要么花时间休整
or if I think that is just procrastination.
要么我只是有拖延情绪
I say it's OK.For 5 minutes.Just push.
我说没事 就5分钟 坚持住就行
And very often that 5 minutes start an upward spiral.
这5分钟往往会让产生一个向上的螺旋
Not through the mind.Not through the heart.
不是通过思想 不是通过心灵
Through action.
而是通过行动
The 5 minute take-off- probably the most useful technique
5分钟起步可能是克服拖延
for overcoming procrastination.
最有用的技巧了
Just do it- in other words.
换句话说 就是放手去做
Reward yourself.You know businesses are built...
奖励自己 你们都懂得生意是一点一滴累积起来的
can you imagine a business without a reward?
你能想象没有奖励的生意吗
Well,think about the self ink.
就像是自动回墨
You are in certain business.You want to motivate yourself.
你在从事某业务 想要激励自己
So reward yourself.
那就奖励自己
OK,I'm going to do three hours of work now,
好了 我要工作3小时
and then allow myself a three hour meal
然后在食堂吃一顿3小时大餐
in the dining hall as a reward.
作为奖励
Or I'm going to really work hard on Friday
或者我这周五要用功
so that Saturday I can go out.
这样周六就能出去玩了
That's OK.You know,we do it in any other place.
没问题 我们做其他事也这样
But no again,
但不行
we say no I need to be inspired for this problem set.
我得受到激励 才能制作出题库
Yes,sometimes.
也许有时候是
But sometimes we are not that inspired.
但有时候我们并没有得到激励
And rewards are certainly legit and important.
奖励当然也很重要
Go public.Throw your knapsack over the wall.
公布出去 破釜沉舟
Tell people what you are going to achieve.
告诉大家你的目标
This is exactly what I did in 1995
我在1995年就是这么做的
when I first decided to teach workshops in psychology.
我第一次决定教授心理学专题讨论会
I was working in Singapore at that time.
我当时在新加坡工作
I called up my boss,Mr.Hugh Hang.
我打电话给我的领导 Hugh Hang先生
And I said to him,"Hugh,I want to teach workshop.
我告诉他"Hugh 我想开一次专题讨论会
Or two day workshops- one on leadership,
为时两天的讨论会 一天关于领导力
one on the pursuit on excellence and success."
另一天关于追求卓越与成功"
And he said,"that's great.
他说"太好了
I think it will really help the employees.
这会对员工帮助很大
When do you want to do it by?"
你想什么时候进行?"
I said,"July 1." This was January of 1995.
我说"7月1日" 当时是1995年1月
And he said,"fine." Put down the phone,I called in...
他说"好的"挂上了电话 我是打电话说的
I was here at the time.I called him up.
我当时在这里 是打电话给他的
And as soon as I put down the phone,I said,"Oh.Shoot.
我一放下电话 就脱口而出"天啊
What have I just done?" One of the best things that I ever did.
我干了什么?"我做过最正确的事
Because I went public with it.
因为我公布了目标
I threw my knapsack over the wall.
破釜沉舟
And I had to start working,whether I liked it or not.
不得不着手开工 无论我是否喜欢
And that helped me overcome procrastination.
这帮助我克服了拖延
Because I knew that I wanted to teach at some point.
因为我知道自己想开设专题讨论会
But when I went public with it,
一旦对外公布
in a sense,it "forced" me to do it.
某种意义上 我就被迫去做了
And I gave the workshop.
后来我开设了讨论会
It wasn't the best workshop in July of 1995,but I did it.
虽然不是1995年7月最棒的专题讨论会 但我办到了
And I worked extremely hard toward it.The team approach.
我准备得很努力 团队方法
The best predictor,for example of maintaining an exercise regime
比如 坚持训练课程最好的方法之一
is doing it with other people.
就是和其他人一起进行
Now this is not right of everyone.
可能不是每个人都适用
Some people-
有些人
exercise is something that they want to do by themselves,
喜欢一个人进行训练
just with their Discman or just by themselves at home.
一个人听着随身听 或者独自在家进行
And that's OK.However,
完全没问题 但是对大多数人来说
for most people,doing it with other people actually helps.
与别人一起进行会有所帮助
It also helps to write down- this is a commitment.
书面写下也很有用...等于建立了契约
Write down goals.Divide and conquer.
把目标写下来 分阶段进行
Break down the achievement.
一一击破
Remember Langer's research? Write these things down.
还记得Langer的研究吗 把目标写下来
Make a list.It actually helps most people.
列一张表 对多数人来说很有用
And finally,permission to recreate.
最后一点 允许自己娱乐消遣
What that means is give yourself permission to be human;
准许自己为人
give yourself permission to procrastinate at times as well;
有时候拖延一下也未尝不可
give yourself permission to recover.
允许自己休整
You are not a machine; we are not machines.
你不是机器 我们不是机器
We need to understand the constraint of you of nature.
我们需要了解能力的范畴
Because if we don't understand it,if we don't respect nature,
否则就是违背自然
nature is not going to respect us,
自然就会报复我们
and we are going to pay a price,in terms of our productivity,
让我们付出代价 效率降低
our creativity as well as our happiness- the ultimate currency.
失去创造力与幸福感 也就是我们终极货币
I want to show you a quick excerpt
我给大家放一段视频
by my favorite,Ellen DeGeneres.
是我最喜欢的Ellen DeGeneres
And this is the end,the end of her show on procrastination,
这是一期有关拖延的节目的结尾部分
which I highly,highly recommend you.
强烈推荐大家看看
You can find it in any of the video stores around here.
任意音像店里都能找到
So here she is- the end of her show
这期节目时长一小时 主题是拖延
after she's talked about procrastination for over an hour.
这是结尾部分
The one and only.
唯一的
Ellen DeGeneres "Here and Now":
Ellen DeGeneres《此时此地》
We are doing all these things to squeeze things together
我们想尽一切办法把事情挤在一起做
so we can save time.
以节省时间
And I don't know about you but I don't have anymore time.
我不知道你们怎么样 但我时间不够了
I have less time.
我时间越来越少了
But let's just say we could save up a whole chunk of time
假设我们能省出一堆时间
and set it aside.
空闲了出来
You know what we'd do with it?
然后拿它干什么呢
Nothing.Nothing at all.
什么也不做
Isn't that the point to be able to do nothing at all?
什么也不做 意义不正是如此吗
But we're not guaranteed that later on chunk of time.
但以后的一堆时间是无法保证的
All we have is HERE AND NOW
我们能控制的只有此时此地
and that's why procrastination feels so right!
所以拖延的感觉才这么好
Procrastination is not the problem.
拖延不是问题
It is the solution.It is the universe's way of saying
是解决方法 是全世界共同的表达
"Stop.Slow down.You move too fast.Listen to the music.
"停下 慢点 你太快了 听听音乐
Whoa whoa,listen to the music
什么 听音乐
(lyrics of a song by Doobie Brothers "Listen to the Music")."
(杜比兄弟《听音乐》)
What im trying to say is if you leave here tonight
我的意思是 如果你今晚离开这时
and you don't remember anything else that I've said,
不记得我说的任何话
leave here and remember this: PROCRASTINATE NOW.
只要记住这句就行:现在就拖延
DON'T PUT IT OFF.Thank you."
别拖延拖延 谢谢"
Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar:OK.Out of everything that I teach,
好了 我教的所有课程中
this lecture this topic is the most personally meaningful to me.
这节课这一主题对我来说意义最深远
Because in many ways,my shift,my journey from perfectionism-
因为从许多方面 我的转变 从完美主义到...
and it's an on-going journey,
这一转变仍在进行
a journey that goes on right now as we speak-
此时此刻正在发生
my journey from perfectionism to the pursuit of excellence
从完美主义转变成追求卓越
is the most intimately linked
这一转变与我的快乐历程
with my journey toward becoming happier.
紧密相连
So I want to share with you some personal things
我想给大家讲讲
that I've been through.
我的一些个人经历
Some of them are in my book.
有些已经写在书里了
But I want to expand this- the story beyond squash.
我想再扩展一下 不止壁球的故事
So I started playing squash at the age of 11,
我11岁开始打壁球
which was after giving up an illustrious,
放弃成为篮球明星
passionate career as a basketball star.
这一前途光明 充满激情的事业
It was about that time
那时
when I realized that NBA was not going to be a...
我意识到NBA的梦想
was not going to happen for me.
无法实现了
I started playing squash
我转而开始打壁球
and almost immediately started playing every day.
几乎每天都打
My days revolved; my life at that time revolved around squash.
当时我的生活围绕着壁球转
I would wake up at 5 am in the morning and go for a run.
每天早上5点起床 出门跑步
Would come home.Have my food.Go to school.
回到家 吃早餐 上学
Right after school- it was next to the squash,
放学后 我会去打壁球
not far from the squash court,I would go to the squash court,
学校就在壁球场附近 距离不远
play with my coach,work out in the gym,play games.
与教练一起练习 在健身房锻炼 打比赛
And then,late afternoon,
一直到傍晚
I would go home,do my homework and then go to sleep.
才回家做作业 然后睡觉
For years,this was my pattern.
好几年一直如此
It was difficult.It was tough,especially the interval training-
那段时间很苦 很艰难 尤其是间歇训练
work out with my coach.
与教练一起锻炼
However,it was nothing- the toughness was nothing compared
但是 这些训练强度与我心理上遇到的问题比
to the emotional difficulties at the time.
根本不算什么
I was constantly,constantly with almost no recovery,no reprieve
我不断受到压力
I was constantly stressed.
而且几乎没有休整
There was always a knot that I felt in my stomach.
我总觉得胃里有个结
It was real,as if there was a ball here.
感觉很真实 就好像有个球在那里
The knot was especially pronounced,
每次训练情况不好
especially difficult after a poor performance in practice
与我给自己设定的标准产生距离时
when it didn't match to the standards that I had for myself.
这个结尤其明显 尤其难受
And it was almost never matched.
而距离几乎一直存在
The knot was at its severest during tournaments.
比赛期间情况尤为严重
Very often,I would get to a final of an important tournament
经常 我闯入了一场重要比赛的决赛
and choke and lose the final,
突然发挥失常 输了决赛
even at times when I was supposed to win- on paper at least.
哪怕理论上能赢的比赛都输了
That knot didn't go away.
那个结没有消失
When it went away,it was only for very short periods of time.
就算消失 也只是很短的一段时间
But I knew that the knot would go away.
但我相信它会消失的
And I was sustained by the belief,by the vision,
当时有一个信念 一个愿望
by my personal mission at the time of winning
一个目标一直支撑着我
the Israeli National Championships.
要赢得以色列全国锦标赛
I said to myself,
我对自己说
"if I win this,then I'll be happy; then I'll be calm.
"如果我赢了 我就会快乐 就会平静
And it's all going to be worth it."
一切付出都是值得的"
Why? Because no pain,no gain.
为什么 因为只有付出 才有收获
In 1986,I reached the final of Israeli National Championships
1986年 我闯入了以色列全国锦标赛决赛
and I lost.
但我输了
I was devastated.I was devastated,
我身心交瘁
even though I was the youngest player to ever reach the final,
虽然我是有史以来最年轻的决赛选手
even though I'd beaten players higher than me on the rankings.
虽然我击败了排名高于我的选手
I was devastated for months.
我一蹶不振好几个月
But still,I went on- no pain,no gain.
不过最终 我还是挺过来了 只有付出 才有收获
And I continued to train and work hard.
我继续刻苦训练
In 1987,I met the same player in the final and this time I won.
1987年 我在决赛中又碰到了同一个对手 这次我赢了
I was ecstatic,joyous,happier than I ever remember myself being
我欣喜若狂 从未如此快乐过
And at that moment,I said to myself,"it all paid off.
那一刻 我对自己说"付出终有回报
It was all worth it.
都是值得的
Because now I was ready to be happy."
我会变得快乐"
I went out with my friends and family,and we celebrated.
我跟亲朋好友外出庆祝
And about 4 hours later after the celebration,I went back home.
庆祝会后4小时 我回到家
I went back home,and wanted to,before going to sleep,
我回到家 睡觉前
just for one last time savor,enjoy that feeling of joy,
想再回味一下
of ecstasy,of pure bliss that I earned.
胜利的喜悦与快乐
And I sat down on my bed and I suddenly,without any warning,
我坐在床上 突然毫无预警地
the exact same feeling,the exact same emotion,
完全相同的感觉 完全相同的情感
the exact same knot returned.
那个结又回来了
And I started to cry- not the same tears of joy
我放声大哭 不是4小时前
that I cried 4 hours earlier,but tears of pain and helplessness.
喜极而泣的泪水 而且痛苦无助的泪水
The knot returned.
那个结又回来了
And I thought,"well,maybe it's the high follow...
我想"也许这是高潮后的失落"
It's the low following high." And I hoped it would go away.
我指望结会再消失
But it didn't go away.
但它没有
And a few weeks later,
几周后
I realized what it was and this time I really nailed it.
我意识到它究竟是什么 这一次我彻底搞清楚了
I understood.
我明白了
I would have to be the world champion to really be happy.
我要成为世界冠军才能真正快乐
I graduated from high school.
高中毕业后
I had two years before I had to enlist in the military.
离我入伍服役还有2年空余时间
And I took off to England.
我去了英格兰
In England,I lived in London
住在伦敦
and joined Stripes which was the squash club in Ealing Broadway,
加入了位于Ealing大道的Stripes壁球俱乐部
where Jansher Khan,world champion at the time used to train.
当时世界冠军Jansher Khan常常在那训练
Because I said,"this is my goal; this is my objective."
因为我对自己说"这是我的目标"
And I would come in every single day
我每天都去俱乐部
and watch Jansher Khan and imitate him.
看Jansher Khan训练 模仿他
Whatever he did,I would do.
无论他做什么 我都照做
So he ran 7 miles each morning; I would ran 7 miles each morning.
他每天早上跑7英里 我也每天早上跑7英里
He would go to the court,work out in the gym;
他去壁球场 去健身房锻炼
I did exactly what he did.
我都照做
He played numerous games with other players;
他与其他选手进行无数场比赛
I would play numerous games with other players.
我也与其他选手进行无数场比赛
And he had training partners.
他有训练搭档
And I wasn't good enough at that time to be his training partner,
当时我水平还不够成为他的训练搭档
so I would just hang out there and once in a while,
所以只是偶尔去一次
once in a while when there was no one around,he would say,
有时候 只有我们两人时 他会说
"come,Tal,let's play a little bit." And we would play.
"来吧 Tal 我们对打看看" 于是我们会打一会儿
And I went back to the drawing board after each game with him.
每次与他比赛后 我都会从头再来
And I would play harder and train harder.
更努力的打球 更努力的练习
Just what he did- because to be like him,
因为要像他那样
to be the world champion,I would have to train like him.
成为世界冠军 我就必须像他一样训练
And I trained harder and harder.And I got better and better.
我训练越来越刻苦 表现也越来越好
And after about six months,
六个月后
I became good enough to be one of his training partners.
我的水平能够成为他的训练搭档了
And after a year,I became his regular training partner.
一年后 我成为了他的常规搭档
I would travel with him around the world.
我跟着他去了世界各地
Wherever he would play tournaments,we would train before.
只要他有比赛 我们都会进行训练
However,injuries began to creep in.Why?
但是 伤痛开始出现 为什么
Because Jansher had built up from,literally the age of three,
因为Jansher从三岁就开始锻炼
he built up his stamina,his fitness;
他的耐力体格 都是日积月累锻炼出来的
and for me,it was all or nothing.
而我 要么全有要么全无
Either I trained like an amateur or don't train at all,
要么进行业余训练 要么完全不训练
or I trained like the world champion.
要么像世界冠军一样训练
And my body couldn't handle it.And I started injuries.
我的身体无法承受 开始出现伤痛
Initially,mild injuries- ankle.So I took two days off.
一开始 只是踝关节小伤 所以我休息了两天
Or my knee started hurting a little bit-
如果膝盖有伤
you know,three,four days off.
那就休息三四天
Back was a bit uncomfortable.Nothing serious.
恢复训练以后会有一点不舒服 不过不严重
I would go back to training.All or nothing.
我会继续训练 要么全有要么全无
Either I don't train at all or I train like the world champion.
要么不训练 要么像世界冠军一样训练
Cause I want to be like him.
因为我想成为他那样
And I continue doing that for 4 years.Injuries on and off.
就这样坚持了4年 伤痛时有出现
Getting more and more severe,until the age of 20.21-
越来越严重 直到我20 21岁时
the doctor told me,"you have a choice.
医生告诉我"你面临一个选择
You can continue training and playing professional squash,
你可以继续训练 打职业壁球赛
but then you are risking your back
但你的背部会非常危险
and you probably need to be operated on very soon.
可能很快就需要动手术
Or you can give up professional squash."
要么就放弃职业壁球"
with an extremely heavy heart,I gave up professional squash.
怀着沉重的心情 我放弃了职业壁球
I gave up my dream,applied to college,and came here.
放弃了我的梦想 申请入学 来到了这里
Here,the exact same pattern continued-
同样的模式又发生了
only before it was squash;
只不过以前是壁球
now it was academics that became the central part of my life.
现在学术成了我生活的中心
The knot returned,very shortly after freshman week.
开学才一周 那个结又回来了
Because every paper had to be perfect.
因为每一篇论文我都力求完美
Every word had to be read and summarized.
书上每一个词都要阅读并总结
Every assignment had to be executed immaculately.
每一次作业都要毫无偏差地完成
All or nothing.And I was unhappy.
要么全有 要么全无 我不快乐
And it was on one day during my sophomore year.
在我大二时的某一天
I was a 23 year old sophomore,where I said to myself,
当时我23岁 我对自己说
"enough.Enough.Here I am,in such a wonderful place,
"够了 我身在名校
with such wonderful students,such wonderful teachers.
有这么多出色的同学 优秀的导师
Such a privilege.And I am so unhappy.
应该感到荣幸 但我一点也不快乐"
I don't think it is something that is external.
我觉得这不是外部问题
I must understand myself better.
我必须更好地了解自己
And it was at that point that
于是
I decided to switch my concentration to philosophy and psychology
我转而研究哲学与心理学
wanting to understand the meaning of a happy life,
希望了解快乐生活的意义
wanting to understand how I could become happier
了解如何才能更快乐
and why I was not.
为什么我不快乐
And it was very quickly that I realized,
很快我意识到
that I understood that I was engaged,
我发现自己从事...
or suffering from something that is so common,
或者说遭受到某种普遍
so pervasive and so misunderstood.
且错误的观念折磨
Perfectionism.
完美主义
This is what I want to talk about today,
这就是今天
and what I want to talk about in the next lecture.
及下节课的主题
This notion of perfectionism
完美主义的概念
and what the research has to say about it.
以及对完美主义的研究
Now there is no perfectionist,
人无完人
there is no one person who is on this extreme,
没有人会处于糟糕的极端
nor there is a person who's on the excellence extreme
也没有人会处于卓越的极端
which I will depict later.
这点我等会儿会细讲
The key is how do I become happier
关键是 如何变得更快乐
and I become happier by being less and less perfectionistic.
随着我渐渐脱离完美主义 我变得更快乐了
Perfectionism is not about giving up ambition.
完美主义并不是说要放弃志向
I'm as ambitious,
我有志向
or possibly more ambitious than I was at age of 16 or 23.
甚至可能比16或23岁时志向更远大
It's about having a different approach
而是说对人生历程
toward the journey of our life,
对走出的每一步 尤其是对失败
toward each step of the way- specifically,toward failure.
采取一种不同的方法与态度
So what I'm going to talk about is first of all,
所以我要谈的第一点
define it so that we understand it.
先定义以便理解
Because it is misunderstood.
因为它常常被误解
I'm going to talk about characteristics.
我会谈谈完美主义的特征
We are going to get to that next time only.
我们下节课才会讲
The characteristics- what it means to be a perfectionist?
特征...成为完美主义者代表了什么?
Then I'm going to talk about the consequences.
然后我还会讲讲后果
And then,how it's possible to be both successful and happy.
以及如何保持成功与快乐的平衡
Again,the question we ask in goal setting lecture,
我们在目标设定课上问的问题
the question that essentially we are asking throughout the class-
这一问题我们在课堂上会经常重复
it's not about giving up success;
不是为了放弃成功
it's not about giving up the conventional currency.But
放弃日常生活中的金钱
it's about also enjoying the ultimate currency more importantly.
而是更好地享受我们的幸福
Because it is the ultimate currency.
因为它是终极货币
Then we understand what is the source of perfection;
然后我们理解完美主义的源头是什么
where does it come.
它来自哪里
Because if we understand where it comes from,
因为如果我们了解了它是如何产生的
we are more likely to be able to overcome it.
才更有可能克服它
And then,most importantly,how do we overcome it?
然后 最重要的是 如何克服
And how do we help other people overcome perfectionism?
如何帮助别人克服完美主义
And again,not giving up their ambition,not giving up hard work,
不是让他们放弃志向 或者停止努力工作
not giving up pain of failure- because that's inevitable.
也不是消除失败时的痛苦 这是不可避免的
But simply have a more rational,a more helpful,
而是获得一种更理性 更有益
a more empowering approach toward failure.
更可控的处理失败的方法
OK.So let's get to work.I need a volunteer.
好了 我们开始前 我需要一名志愿者
I need a volunteer,but before you put your hand up,
你们举手前 注意我的要求
it's a very special kind of volunteer.
我要一个很特别的志愿者
I need a volunteer who is a very good artist,
我需要一个很棒的艺术家
a volunteer who can draw really well.
绘画非常出色
No pressure here,right? A volunteer who can draw really well
不要有压力 好吗 要一个画画很棒
and who will actually come here and demonstrate.
且愿意上来展示的志愿者
Now remember it takes courage to come up to the stage
要上台来需要一定勇气
but courage is not about not having fear;
有勇气并不代表不害怕
it's about having fear and going ahead anyway.
而是害怕但仍勇往直前
So do I have a volunteer? I have a volunteer.
有人自愿吗 有一个志愿者
Won't you come up? (Applause)
你上来好吗
OK.Hi.What's your name? Vincent.
你好 怎么称呼 Vincent
Are you a VS concentrator? (Inaudible)
你是VS专业的吗
Don't tell me you are an economics.OK.
别告诉我你是学经济的 好的
What are you? Biology.OK.Good.(Laugh) All right.
那你是什么专业的?生物 很好
So biology- you have to draw many diagrams.
生物学也要画许多图表
That's why I was...
所以我...
Well in Ec you also have to draw diagrams I guess.
经济学也得画图标吧
So it would've been fine,too.
所以也没关系
All right.Are you ready for this?
好了 准备好了吗
You still have the opportunity to going sit down.
最后一次机会让你回到位子上
You are sure you want to...
你确定要...
(Vincent: But I want to conquer my fear.) All right! Yes,good.
- 但我想战胜恐惧 - 好的 很好
All right.Are you ready for this,Vincent? You sure? All right.
好了 准备好了吗 Vincent?你确定 好
Here's what I want you to do now.
以下是我要你做的
I don't know if I want to do this to you though,you know.
我不知道是不是真的想这样对你
All right,but I am going to do it to you anyway.
但是我也只能这样了
I want you to draw here on this part of the board.
请在黑板的这边画...
I want you to draw...
请画...
Are you ready for this? You sure? OK.
准备好了吗 你确定?好的
I want you to draw a circle.
请画一个圆
Take your time.Take your time.No hurry.
慢慢来 不急
You can also erase and put back.
可以擦了重画
But I want to you draw- give your best shot here-
拿出你的看家本事
I want you to draw a circle.
画一个圆
We have half an hour.No hurry.
我们还有半小时时间 不急
The meantime we'll meditate.(Laugh) Yeah.
我们边冥想边等你
I didn't mean it literally half an hour,
我不是真的说半小时
but...OK.(Laugh) Use it as a time-in.That's all.
不过...好的 就当是练习时间
A circle! Vincent,well done! Ooh hoo! (Applause)
一个圆 Vincent 画得漂亮
You are not done yet.
还没完呢
Hey hey! Woah woah woah woah.
等等
Don't run away on me now.
先别急着走
OK.So I'm putting a line here.
好的 我在这画一条线
What I'd like you to do here is draw something else.
这边要画其他东西
So you are ready for it? I would like you to draw another circle,
准备好了吗 请画另一个圆
but this time as you drew it,
不过这次画的时候
as you think you drew it when you were 3 years old.
当作你三岁时候画的样子
3 years old.Again,take your time.
3岁 慢慢来
Metaphorically speaking,
想象一下
take your time and draw a circle as you think you drew it
你三岁时候
when you were 3 years old.
画的圆是什么样子的
All right.Yeah.
好的
And that's when his parents said,"Van Gogh was reborn."
于是你父母说"梵高重现人间"
Can you draw it as you drew it when you were 3 years old,please?
能画一个你三岁时候画的圆吗
(Laugh) I know there are many talented people here,
我知道在座各位才华横溢
but we want some real...OK.All right.
但我们想要些真实...很好
Still,very talented 3 years old.OK.All right.
不过还是一位三岁神童 好的
Good! Good! (Laugh) Now I want you to do one more thing.
很好 现在请再帮我一个忙
I want you to draw here another circle,this time as you drew,
再画一个圆
or you think you drew,
这次画的时候
or you tried to draw when you were 1 year old.OK.
把你当成一岁的孩子
Still a very talented 1 year old,but a 1 year old nevertheless.
一岁神童啊 不过是一岁孩子了
Good.All right.Now Vincent,I...
很好 现在Vincent 我...
The one thing that I really don't like doing teaching-
当老师有一件是我不喜欢做
I love to teach,
我喜欢教书
but the one thing that I really don't like doing- is grading.
但有一件事我不喜欢 就是打分
I hate grading.
我讨厌打分
But you know,as a teacher,you have to do it.
但作为老师 不得不做
You have to do it.
必须打分
So I'm going to have to grade you.
所以我要给你的画打分了
I'm sorry.(Vincent: It's OK.) I'm sorry.
- 抱歉 - 没关系
I look at this entity,and what I see is,
我看着这样东西 我看到的是
what I see is,is a circle actually!
我看到的是 真的是一个圆
You know if I put a line in the middle,
如果我在中间画一条线
you know more or less that equidistance from that point,
差不多都是等距的
if I put a point here- it's actually very good!
如果我在这儿画一个点...真的很不错
Very good,Vincent!Well done! I'm proud of you.
非常好 Vincent 画得好 我真为你骄傲
Well done! You passed.Yes,exactly! (Applause)
干得好 你及格了 没错
But you know,I can't help but looking beyond,and I get here.
但是我往这看
And you know,I am trying to find the right word here
我想找个合适的词来形容
and what would the right word be? Disaster,maybe?
哪个词?"灾难"也许?
I mean,Vincent,please! This is not a circle.
Vincent 拜托 这不是圆
And this? I'm sorry.I'm sorry.I told...
还有这个?抱歉 抱歉
It's tough being a teacher.You know it's...
我说了 老师不好当
But I have a question for you,Vincent.
不过我想问你个问题 Vincent
I have an important question for you.
非常重要的问题
Could you have gotten to drawing a real circle
如果没有经过成千上万给失败的圆
without having drawn hundreds and thousands of failed circles?
你能画出这个真正的圆吗
In other words,could you have gotten here without being here?
换句话说 没有这两步 你能达到这步吗
Absolutely not.There is no other way to succeed.
当然不能 成功没有捷径
Thank you very much,Vincent.(Applause)
非常感谢 Vincent
Learn to fail or fail to learn- there is no other way.
学会失败 从失败中学习 这是唯一的途径
You know I'm a psychologist and you know what a psychologist do?
我是一名心理学家 你们知道心理学家干什么吗
Psychologists watch people.
心理学家观察人
And I watch you every time you come to class.
你们每次进教室我都会观察
And I watch you very very closely.
非常仔细地观察
And you know what I see?
知道我看到了什么吗
Again,this takes a lot of insight,experience,wisdom,
这需要极高的洞察力 经验及智慧
but you know what I see every time when you come into the class?
知道每次你们进教室 我看到了什么吗
That you all are very good walkers.
我看到你们所有人走路非常优雅
Terrific.
了不起
You know in fact what you do is you come in
你们走进教室
and you lift you left leg and then you just,
抬起左腿
your ankle slightly is moved up and very gracefully-
踝关节微微往上 然后优雅地
as you put it down,you lift your back heel.
慢慢放下 抬起后脚的脚跟
You did it so beautifully.So elegantly.
走得非常优美 非常优雅
And you know what? You pretend as you are not even noticing it.
还装作没有注意到
So the same time,you are talking to a friend.
一边走一边与朋友交谈
Some of you are even chewing gum at the same time,
有些人还同时嚼口香糖
just more than Einstein could do.
连爱因斯坦都办不到
And then you lift up your back leg and again,so gracefully,
然后你们又抬起后腿 如此优雅
just you know,you bend your knee slightly.This action.
稍稍弯曲膝盖 这一动作
And you move your arm at the same time.It's a beauty.
同时挥动手臂 太美了
And then you just swing your hips slightly.
然后微微扭动臀部
You know just this action.
像这样
Have you considered a career of modeling?
你们有没有考虑过转行当模特?
I mean really! Nice! And you put here.
我是说真的 漂亮 然后继续走
Then you are talking.You are smiling.
边走边说话 微笑
And you pretend as if there's no effort involved.
假装这一系列动作都是信手拈来
Well done! Yes! You deserve it! Absolutely!
漂亮 你们值得表扬
But here is the question: could you have gotten to this stage,
但是问题来了 如果没有成千上万次的摔倒
to being such good walkers
你们能走到这里
without having fallen hundreds and thousands of times?
走得如此优雅吗
Not even Vincent could have reached that stage without it.
连Vincent都不行
It's not possible.Learn to fail or fail to learn.
这是不可能的 学会失败 从失败中学习
And as kids,we know it.
我们小时候都知道
And you know,
小时候
we fall down and maybe we cry a little bit if it hurts,
我们摔倒了 疼的话可能会哭鼻子
but we get up again.
但是马上又站起来了
We fall down.And we laugh.
摔倒了 还会笑
In fact,let's see an example.Someone is learning how to walk.
来看个例子 有人在学走路
[Video]
[视频]
Man: Go get mommy.
去妈妈那
Go get her.Go get mommy.
去她那儿 去找妈妈
Woman: Good job! Good job!
太棒了
Man: Hey Sophie!
Sophie
Woman: Can you walk back to daddy? Oops.
能走回爸爸那儿吗 哎呀
Give me your hand.
把手给我
Man: Slow down.Slow down.
慢点 慢慢来
Woman: (Laugh) Yay! So hyper.
好紧张
Man: Go get mommy.Go get mommy.
去妈妈那儿 找妈妈去
Go get mommy.Go get her.
找妈妈去 找妈妈去
Man: Take your time,baby! Take your time,baby girl!
慢慢来 宝贝 慢慢来 好姑娘
Mommy: Slow down.
慢点
Are you excited that you can walk?
会走路了 激动吗
Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar:The joy of learning.The joy of...
学习的喜悦
Where is it? Where is it? Where does it go?
这种喜悦上哪儿去了 去哪儿了
Well it goes away because we come to a certain age
它消失了 因为我们到了一定年纪
when we begin to understand other people are watching us,
开始意识到别人在看我们
and then the image kicks in.
开始产生种种想法
"I'm not going to try,because what if I fall?"
"我不要试 万一摔倒怎么办"
Or "I'm not going to ask her out,because what if she says no?"
或者"我不要约她出去 万一她拒绝怎么办"
"Oh no no no.I'm not going to try for this play,
"哦 不不 我不要演这出戏
because hardly anyone gets that."
万一没人看懂怎么办"
"Oh I'm not going to share,
"哦 我不要分享经历
because what if they don't like what I have to say."
万一有人不喜欢怎么办"
Or "everyone is so smart.I'm not going to speak up."
又或者"大家都这么聪明 我还不献丑了"
And we avoid instead of coping.
我们开始逃避而不是应对
And that affects our self esteem,our confidence,our resilience,
这会影响我们的自尊 信心 乐观精神
our happiness levels in the long term.
长期的快乐指数
Or we go on a date.And everything has to be so perfect.
约会时一切必须很完美
So perfect.
非常完美
Forgetting how we learn how to eat in the first place.
忘了我们第一次学吃饭是什么样子
Learn to fail or fail to learn.
学习失败 从失败中学习
This is not actually concrete recommendation for your first date.
这不是第一次约会的实在建议
I don't think it will work.
恐怕行不通
But remember,remember how we learnt.
但记得我们是如何学习的
There is no other way.No other way to grow.No other way to learn.
别无他法 成长没有捷径 学习也没有捷径
No other way to become more resilient,happier,more successful.
乐观 快乐 成功更没有捷径
Have I said this before? This is my personal mantra
我以前说过这个吗 这是我的私人祷文
that I repeat to myself over and over again,
我常常一遍又一遍对自己诵读
especially after failures,especially before doing things
尤其是遇到失败
when I'm afraid to do it,when I said
或者需要克服恐惧
"well,maybe I shouldn't do."
出现"也许我不该做"这类想法时
Because what happens if...? Well,what happens if?
因为万一...万一什么?
what happens if is the worst case scenario: I learn.
万一最坏的情况发生了会怎么样:我学到了
Worst case scenario: it hurts.
最坏的情况 很伤心
But I'll bounce back up again.
但我会复原
You know I bounced back after Rina.
Rina事件后我也恢复了
I can handle anything.
我能应付任何事
"Wei Ji",the Chinese character for crisis,
汉字"危机"
has two parts: the first part is danger-
由两部分组成:第一部分指危险
this is the top character;
是上面那个字
the bottom character,opportunity.
下面那个字代表机遇
There is danger of failing.
有失败的危险
And wherever there is a crisis,
但有危险的地方
,to learn and grow.
就能学习 成长
Elbert Hubbard: "The greatest mistake a man can make
Elbert Hubbard说过"一个人能犯的最大错误
is to be afraid of making one."
就是害怕犯错"
I want to show you an example of a person who had made mistakes,
我想给大家举个例子 有一个人犯过错
who failed time and time and again.
失败了一次又一次
In fact,I was thinking of labeling that person
我甚至想给他授予
or giving him the position of ultimate failure.
失败大王称号
And here is why.
原因如下
At the age of 22,already- just started a new job,lost it.
22岁时 刚找到新工作 就失业了
Didn't leave- he lost it.
不是辞职 是失业
At the age of 23,decided to go into politics
23岁时 他决定投身政治
because he wasn't doing well in other jobs.
因为其他工作他都不在行
But didn't make it there either.
但是也没有成功
And then he went back to business,didn't make it there.
于是继续回去经商 又没有成功
At the age of 27,it was just too much for him.
27岁时 压力太大
Just too much- and he collapsed.
他崩溃了
Had a nervous breakdown.
精神崩溃
But then got up again after falling.
但又重新站起来了
And at the age of 34,7 years after his nervous breakdown,
7年后 他34岁时
he ran for congress- wasn't even close.
竞选国会议员 名落孙山
Didn't make it.
没有成功
At the age of 39,hasn't learned the lesson yet.
39岁时 他还没有学乖
And he was defeated again for congress.
又一次竞选议员失败
And then he said,"let me go try higher."
他说"让我试试更高层的"
At the age of 46,what a loser! Doesn't learn,does he? OK.
46岁时 真失败啊 还没学乖
Yeah.It's OK.Learn to fail.Fail to learn.
没关系 学会失败 从失败中学习
But I mean you are 46 years old,c'mon! Give it up already.
你都46岁了 适可而止吧
At the age of 47,he tried to be nominated for the Vice President
到了47岁 他试图竞选副总统
Didn't learn.Didn't make it.
还没学乖 又失败了
So at the age of 50,he tried again for Senate.
到了50岁 他试图竞选参议员
And then he almost gave up.But he didn't.
他几乎想放弃了 但最终没有
And at the age of 51,
到了51岁
he became the 16th President of the United States.
他成了美国第16任总统
Arguably the most important President this country has ever had.
大概是这个国家历史上最有影响力总统
And through it all and he talks about it,
他谈起这段经历时说
"it was difficult to fail."Of course he had victories.
"失败让人痛苦"当然 他的确有成功过
You know I simplified the process.It was difficult to fail.
我简化了他的生平 失败让人痛苦
He did not enjoy failing.But he persisted it.
他不享受失败 但还是挺过来了
Because he understood just like every other successful person
因为和历史上其他成功者一样
throughout history has understood and understands:
他懂得
there is no other way to learn; there is no way to grow.
学习别无他法 成长别无他法
Mohandas Gandhi,the subtitle of his book is
甘地 他自传的副标题是
"My Experiments with Truth".
"我的对于真理的实践经历"
He talks about experiments,trying and failing,
他谈到了经历 尝试与失败
trying and failing and succeeding,
尝试 失败与成功
and failing again,and trying again.
再次失败 再次尝试
Those of you who know his story in South Africa-
你们可能听说过他在南非的故事
he tried exactly or very similar to what he later tried in India.
他在南非进行的事业与之后在印度的非常相似
In South Africa,he failed miserably.
在南非 他经历了惨痛的失败
But then he moved over to India and tried there.
但到了印度重新尝试
And there after many failures,
经过无数次的失败
he succeeded in bringing independence to his country.
成功把祖国领向了独立
More than anyone understands the importance of failure.
他比其他人更懂得失败的重要性
"Freedom is not worth having
不涵盖自由犯错的自由
if it does not connote freedom to err."
是不值得拥有的
And when he talks about "freedom to err",
他指的自由犯错
he means it on the national level:
是指国家层面上的
being self-determined,free people.
人民能自主自由
He also means it on the individual level.
同时也是个人层面上的
My favorite author,my favorite writer is George Eliot.
我最喜欢的作者乔治艾略特
Her name was Mary Anne Evans,changed to George Eliot,
她原名玛丽安娜艾凡斯 后来改为乔治艾略特
because at the time,when she published,
因为在当时
mid 19th to late 19th century,
19世纪中晚期
it was very difficult for a woman to be published.
妇女很难出版
George Eliot had this to say:
乔治艾略特说过
"The important work of moving the world forward
"推动世界前进的重任
does not wait to be done by perfect men."
并不是由完人来进行的"或完美女子
Or women.If you read her texts,
读她的文字你会发现
it is the closest to perfection as I've ever encountered,
是我读过的最接近完美的
whether it's Middle March or Daniel Deronda,
无论是《米德尔马契》还是《丹尼尔 德龙达》
which is my favorite book.
是我最喜欢的书
Just do it.Just act.Be prepared to fail.
放手去做 放手行动 准备失败
I want to show you an example.
我给大家举个例子
Once again,a video of a person who understands his imperfections
录像的这位主角懂得自己的不完美
and yet gives himself the permission to fail.
允许自己失败
Here he is.A TV presenter.
一位电视主持人
[Saturday Night Live]
[周六夜现场]
Bennett Brauer:That's right.
没错
Bennett Brauer here with another commentary.
Bennett Brauer又有话要说了
Didn't think the suits would have me back perhaps.
没想到管事的还能让我回来
Thought they'd have my dairy-air replaced
还以为他们会把我的节目
by one of cookie store mannequin.
换成某个曲奇店模型
Well maybe I'm not "the norm".
也许我是不"正常"
I'm not "camera friendly",I don't "wear clothes that fit me",
我不"上镜" 衣着"不合身"
I'm not a "heartbreaker",I haven't had "sex with a woman",
不够"催泪" 从没和"女人上过床"
I don't know "how that works",
不知道"怎么勾搭女人"
I guess I don't "fall in line",I'm not "hygienic".
看来我不"符合要求" 我不讲"卫生"
I don't "wipe properly",I lack "style",
我上厕所"屁股不擦干净" 不够"有型"
I have no "charisma" or "self-esteem",
没有"魅力"没有"自尊"
I don't "own a toothbrush",or "let my scabs heal",
没有"自己的牙刷" "喜欢抠血痂"
I can't "reach all the parts of my body",
我"够不到身体的各个部位"
when I sleep I sweat profusely.
睡觉时汗如雨下
But I guess the "powers that be"
不过我想"掌权的"
will keep signing my pay check at least until Jack and Jane K.
会继续给我发薪水
Viewer start to go for the remote
观众开始起身拿遥控器
so they can get back to commentators
调回新闻评论
who don't "frighten children",
他们不会"吓坏孩子"
who don't "eat their own dandruff",
不会"吃自己的头皮屑"
who don't "pop their whiteheads with a compass
不会"用高中用的指南针
they used in high school".
抠粉刺"
Thank you,Kevin.
谢谢 Kevin
Kevin Nealon: Bennet Brauer,ladies and gentlemen.
女士们先生们 感谢Bennet Brauer
Bennett Brauer: Thank you.
谢谢
Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar:In sports,Bay Brooth,at the time,
运动员Bay Brooth
the most home runs out of the any other player.
曾保持本垒打次数最多的纪录
Held the record for many years.
记录保持了多年
How many people know that he also topped the league 5 years.
有多少人知道他还有另一项记录
5 years he topped the league in strikeouts.
5年来 他也是三振出局第一
Very often the case.Very often the case.
这种情况很常见
That the most successful athletes are also ones
最成功的运动员竟然也是
who have failed the most.
失败最多的运动员
And if you reach for the stance,
一旦你准备击球
you have to be prepared to fail many times.
得做好失败的准备
Or the greatest of them all.
又或者是他们当中最伟大的
(Michael Jordan) Before he learned how to fly,
在乔丹学会飞翔之前
he learned how to walk.
他先学会了走路
Before he learned how to walk,he learned how to crawl.
他学会走路之前 先学会了如何爬行
And he failed many times.
他也失败过许多次
Here he is in his own words,the one and only,Michael Jordan.
来听听他是怎么说的 唯一的迈克尔乔丹
Michael Jordan:I've missed more than 9000 shots in my career.
我的职业生涯投篮失误超过9000次
I've lost almost 300 games.
输了大约300场比赛
26 times,
有26次
I've been trusted to take the game winning shot and missed.
我被委以重任投制胜一球 但失手了
I've failed over and over and over again in my life.
我这一生一次又一次失败
And that is why I succeed.
所以我能获得成功
Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar:Ha.Michael.(Laugh) I love Michael Jordan.
乔丹 我喜欢乔丹
People remember his game winning shot that made him famous.
人们记得让他声名大噪的制胜一球
Was at North Carolina while he shot with the buzzer and they won.
那是在北卡罗来纳州 他最后一投压哨获胜
Do you remember that he had 20,
但你们是否记得他有20次
or did you know that he had 26 game winning shots that he missed?
你们是否知道他有26次压哨失手
Well he failed time and time and again,which is why he succeeds.
他失败了一次又一次 最终获得胜利
There is no other way.
成功别无他法
Thomas Edison.Remember "I failed my way to success"?
爱迪生说过"我从失败中走向成功"
Ten thousand times failures before he invented the light bulb.
他失败了一万多次 才最终发明了电灯泡
But he didn't see them as failures.
但他没有把它们简单地视为失败
He succeeded in showing what doesn't work.
而是成功展示了哪些方法是不可行的
Anita Roddick,founder of the Body Shop,passed away last year.
美体小铺的创始人Anita Roddick 去年刚过世
Did fantastic work.
取得了伟大的成就
Changed business world in many ways,
从诸多方面改变了商业世界
to make more compassionate businesses.
参与了多项慈善事业
Failed time and time and again,and succeeded.
也是失败了许多次后才成功的
No other way.
没有其他方法
Harvard Business School.
河对岸哈佛商学院教授
She was a graduate student here in the psychology department
她是心理学系的硕士研究生
when I was an undergraduate.
当时我还在读本科
And I remember when she was working on her dissertation,
我还记得当时她在写学位论文
cause we had the same advisor.I was working...
我们的导师是同一个人 我和...
We were both working with Richard Hackman.
我俩的导师都是Richard Hackman
And her work was,still is to some extent,in hospitals.
她当时的研究是有关医院的 目前的研究也与医院有关
And what she wanted to understand was how can you help eliminate
她想研究如何才能消除
or at least reduce failure rates in hospitals.Why?
或至少降低医院的失败率 为什么?
Because medical errors cost millions and billions dollars a year.
因为医疗事故一年会损失几百万乃是几十亿美元
And much more importantly,
更重要的是
many people lose their lives as a result of medical errors.
许多人因为医疗事故而丧失
So she wanted to understand this phenomenon
所以她想研究这一现象
and how you can reduce it.
并寻找解决之道
And she was working with Richard Hackman
她的导师是Richard Hackman
who's been doing work for decades on effective groups.
他当时已对有效群组研究了数十年
Those of you who have taken his class,psychology 501,know him.
参加过心理学501号课程的同学应该认识他
If you haven't taken his class,put it on the top of your list.
如果还没有参加过 不妨列为第一选择
And he's done work on teams,on groups for many years.
他对团队和小组进行了多年研究
And what he found was there are certain conditions that
他发现在某些条件下
if they are put into place in an organzation,
如果人们置身于某个组织
the group is more likely to perform well.
更有可能表现优异
Certain conditions.
某些条件
And what Amy Edmondson wanted to do in her dissertation was show
所以Amy Edmondson的论文想要证明
that when hospitals implement Richard Hackman's advice,
如果医院采取Richard Hackman的建议
when they have the conditions that Richard Hackman talks about,
使用Richard Hackman所说的条件
such as a clear,engaging goal for the team,for the group,
比如给予团队明确可行的目标
such as an enabling team structure,
建立有效的团队结构
such as supportive organization,such as effective coaching.
及时的组织支援 高效的训练
When a group has these conditions in place,
当一个团队具备了这些条件
it will not only perform better,
就会表现得更出色
which is the research that Hackman illustrates for decades,
这也是Hackman十几年来的研究结果
they will also commit less medical errors.
而且会减少医疗事故
Very important research.So she did this research.
这是项非常重要的研究 于是她着手研究了
It took her very long time.
花费了很长时间
She went to the field,studied at hospitals.
进行实地调查 在医院研究
And after a long time-
经过很长一段时间
again this was on the 15th floor in William James Hall,
在William James大楼15楼
I remember that- she one day got her results.
我还记得她得到结果的那天
Entered all her data into SPSS,pressed the button.
把数据输入了统计软件 按下了确认
And there was significant statistical difference
两组统计数据
between the two groups.
有明显差异
The group that implemented Hackman's conditions
使用Hackman条件的小组
and the group that did not.
以及不使用Hackman条件的小组
Eureka! She was happy,ecstatic.Years of work.
找到了 她欣喜若狂 几年的工作成果
And she runs to Richard's office,and says to him,
她跑去了Richard的办公室 对他说
"Richard,I got it! Here are the results."
"Richard 我得到结果了 在这里"
He says,"let's see.I want to see." So he looks at it.
他说"让我看看" 他看了一眼
He says,"Amy,that's fantastic! It's very significant result.
说"Amy 太惊人了 结果令人惊讶
It wasn't just borderline.This is great! Fantastic!"
这不仅仅是模凌两可的边界了 太棒了"
And he looks at it,and he says,
他仔细阅读起来
"are you sure these are the results?"
"你确定是这个结果?"
And she said,"yeah! They are highly significant!"
她说"是啊 结果意义重大"
He said,"are you sure?
他又问"你确定?
Did you enter the data again and test it?"
有没有重新输入数据再测试一遍?"
"Yeah,Yeah!" She is very methodical,very hard working.
"有啊"她工作非常有条理 非常努力
She said,"yeah,I did!"
她说"都核对过了"
So he said,"you know,these are certainly significant
于是他说"结果的确意义重大
but they are significant in the opposite direction."
但事实却恰恰相反"
Meaning the hospitals that implemented these conditions that
也就是说使用Hackman条件的医院
Hackman talks about were actually making more medical errors.
反而出了更多医疗事故
Again this ? the phase of decades of research.
这简直给几十年的研究一个大大的耳光
Never specifically about medical errors,
不仅是针对医疗事故
but so many other related topics.
其他很多方面也是如此
And he said,"well,a result is a result.Reality is reality.
于是他说"结果就是结果 现实就是现实
We have to go back to the field and understand why.
我们得回到现场 分析原因
We have to understand this phenomenon."
理解这一现象
So she had to go back to the drawing board- tired,enervated,
于是她从头开始 精疲力竭 衰弱无力
didn't understand what happened,went back to the hospitals,
不理解怎么会这样 又回到了医院
and in almost no time,realized what the issue was.
很快就发现了问题出在哪儿
These hospitals,or groups within these hospitals
这些事故更多的医院 或医院小组
that made more mistakes did not actually make more mistakes.
其实并没有发生更多医疗事故
They reported more mistakes.
而是报告了更多的事故
In fact,the other groups,who on paper made less mistakes,
事实上 其他小组虽然表面上事故少了
actually made many more mistakes.
其实发生了更多的医疗事故
However,they did not report them.
但他们没有汇报
Now how did she know it?
她是怎么发现的呢
Because there are certain mistakes that you cannot hide.
因为有些事故是无法掩盖的
It is very difficult to hide a corpse,for example.
比如 很难掩盖一具尸体
So the mistake,the real major mistakes that were made,
所以这些大事故发生时
they were out,and these groups had to report these.
这些小组不得不汇报
It' not that they made less;
并不是他们事故减少了
they made more mistake but they didn't report.
而是增多了 只不过没有汇报
And then she changed the focus of her research
于是她改变了研究的重心
to the notion of psychological safety.
转向心理安全概念
Psychological safety is the feeling,the experience,
心理安全是一种感觉 经历 空间
the space that you feel in your workplace,in your organization
让你觉得可以在办公地点 在组织内
where you are safe talking about errors and mistakes,
安全地讨论错误与过失
where you feel safe falling down and getting up again.
让你觉得摔倒了也能安全地站起来
And these organizations with their own psychological safety,
有心理安全的组织
they performed better.
会表现地更好
And again,this was in 1999,a lot of research done by her
当时是1999年 她与全世界各国研究人员
and people around the world,
进行了大量研究
showing how groups,organizations with their psychological safety
证明了有心理安全的团队组织
with their employees don't or are not afraid of whistle blowing
他们的雇员不会害怕告密
or not afraid of falling down of making mistakes.
也不会害怕摔倒 或犯错
These organizations are significantly more successful.
这些组织更为成功
These are learning organizations
它们是学习型组织
with the employees constantly learn and grow.
雇员不断地学习成长
Or you learn from your mistakes
从错误中学习
and then the next time you are able to do better.
下一次就能做得更好
Very significant,very important research,
意义重大 影响深远的研究
whether it's for leaders,
无论是领导者
whether it's for parents- many of you will be future parents.
还是家长...你们中很多以后会成为家长
Would you have this psychological safety for your kids,
你们会不会为自己的孩子营造心理安全
while they feel comfortable talking to you about things
让他们毫无约束地告诉你
that they did not do well,about failures.
他们做的不好 失败的事
Because if they do feel comfortable,they are much less likely
因为如果他们愿意跟你说
to enter into this perfectionistic fear of failure.
就不容易进入害怕失败的完美主义
And they are much more likely to be happier as well as successful
而会更快乐 更成功
This is a story about Thomas Watson,
来听听关于Thomas Watson的故事
founder of IBM,one organization that he invented and
他是IBM的创建者 他至今仍旧
reinvented itself numerous times- continues on the daily basis.
每天不断地改造它
And that's why it survives.
所以IBM能发展至今
So there was an employee at the beginning when IBM was founded,
IBM刚成立 还在生产打字机时
when they were making type writers,
有一名员工
an employee made a strategic error.
犯了战略性错误
And the error was that he actually lost IBM a million dollars
给IBM损失了一百万美元
and a million dollars at that time for IBM was a lot of money.
当时对于IBM来说这是一大笔钱
So the next day,after he made that mistake,
于是他犯错后第二天
he comes to see Thomas Watson,the founder,
去找了创始人Thomas Watson
and gives him a letter.
给了他一封信
Thomas Watson opens the letter and reads it
Thomas Watson打开信读了读
and looks at the employee and says,"what is this?"
问那名员工 "这是什么"
He says,"sir,it's my letter of resignation."
他说"先生 这是我的辞职信"
"Why resignation?"
"为什么辞职"
"Sir,I just made a mistake
"先生 我刚犯了个错
that cost your organization a million dollars.
给您的公司造成了一百万美元损失
I don't want...You've been great to me.
我不想...您对我一直很好
I don't want to put you
我不想让您烦恼
through this difficult experience of firing me.
是否要炒了我
So I'm resigning."
所以我主动辞职"
Thomas took the letter and tore it and said,"fire you? Fire you?
Thomas把信撕了 说"炒了你?
I've just invested a million dollars in your education
我刚为您的教育投入了一百万美元
and I'm going to fire you?"
现在我要炒了你?"
Now whether this story is exactly true,or almost true,
无论这则故事是否100%真是 还是部分真实
it's still a story that circulates around IBM,
在IBM公司广为流传
and a story that creates a certain reality in IBM,
在IBM公司营造了良好的氛围
a reality that says "you have to try".
告诉大家"你必须尝试"
There is a similar story in Johnson & Johnson,
世界最成功的公司之一 强生公司
one of the most successful companies in the world,
也有类似的故事
where General Johnson,
Johnson将军
one of the two founders with his other brother,
他与兄弟创建了该公司
also called Johnson- just why it's called Johnson & Johnson.
他们俩都叫Johnson 所以叫强生公司
So Jim Burke was an upcoming employee in Johnson & Johnson,
Jim Burke是强生公司的新人
made a mistake that cost the organization a lot of money
由于一个错误给公司造成了巨大损失
was called in the morning
简朴硬朗的Johnson将军
by General Johnson who was a very austere,very tough man.
一早会见了他
And Jim Burke comes in,you know all shivering and scared.
Jim Burke走进他的办公室 可想而知胆战心惊
He comes in and walks into General Johnson's office.
他走进Johnson将军的办公室
General Johnson walks from around his table,
Johnson将军从桌边
goes to him and says,
走到他面前 说
"congratulation,Jim Burke! Congratulation!"
"恭喜 Jim Burke 恭喜"
"Sir,I just made a mistake,sir."
先生 我刚犯了个错
"Yes,I know.This is the only way to learn.
"是的 我知道 这是学习的唯一方法
The more mistakes you make,the more successful you will be.
现在犯得错越多 将来越有可能成功
Congratulations!"
恭喜"
And Jim Burke was all happy and about to walk out.
Jim Burke非常高兴 正准备离开
And General Johnson says,"oh,just one more thing,Jim:
Johnson将军又说"还有一件事 Jim
if you make the same mistake again,I'm going to fire you."
如果你再犯同样的错 我会炒了你"
But again,a story that goes around Johnson & Johnson
这则关于失败的重要性的故事
about the importance of failure.
在强生公司流传开了
Jim Burke,by the way,
而Jim Burke
became the most successful CEO of Johnson & Johnson.
成为了强生公司最成功的CEO
Thomas Watson- I'm almost done,one minute,almost done:
Thomas Watson 马上就结束了 再给我一分钟
"If you want to increase your success rate,
"如果你想提高成功率
double your failure rate."
就要将失败率翻倍"
We talked about this research.We talked about this research,
我们已经讲过这项研究
the origins of the genius- the most successful,
天才的起源
the most successful artist,
历史上最成功的艺术家
the most successful scientist in history are also the ones
最成功的科学家
who have failed the most times,who have the most duds.
也是失败最多的 经历过最多的失败
It's the Edisons.It's the Davincis.
爱迪生 达芬奇
It's the Michelangelos.It's the Marie Currie.
米开朗基罗 居里夫人
The most successful
最成功的
scientist and artist have also failed the most.
科学家与艺术家 经历过最多的失败
And finally,Klam who did the...
还有 Klam
Jane Klam who did research on people's success in dieting
Jane Klam对节食成功
or people's success in starting an exercise regime,
或成功开始运动的人士进行研究
what she found was the most successful people,
她发现最成功的
people who have been able to persist
有毅力坚持下来的人
are people who have failed on average 5 times before.
都平均经历过5次失败
So they have been on 5 diets and  haven't succeeded.
也就是说他们减肥5次 都没有成功
The fifth one,or the sixth one-
到了第五次 或者第六次
I'm successful and I'm able to sustain it.
才成功并维持住的
The same with the exercise regime.
运动也是如此
Learn to fail or fail to learn.
学会失败 从失败中学习
See you on Thursday.
周四见